e-zpassny.com 2010-12-15

# E-ZPass® New York - Privacy Policy

| 

_E-ZPass_ **®** New York Internet Privacy Policy

> Introduction  
>  Thank you for visiting the _E-ZPass_ **®** New York Customer Service Center (“NYCSC”) website. ACS State & Local Solutions, Inc. (“ACS”) maintains this website on behalf of the New York State Thruway Authority, Metropolitan Transportation Authority Bridges & Tunnels, New York State Bridge Authority (collectively, “New York Authorities”) and the Port Authority of New York & New Jersey (all collectively, “Authorities” or “Authority”). This website is designed to make it easier and more efficient for individuals and businesses to get information about _E-ZPass_ **®** and to maintain their _E-ZPass_ **®** accounts. The Authorities and ACS recognize that it is critical for individuals and businesses to be confident that their privacy is protected when they visit the _E-ZPass_ **®** NYCSC website.
> 
> This policy describes the Authorities’ privacy practices regarding information collected from users of this website. For the New York Authorities, and ACS when acting on behalf of the New York Authorities, this policy is consistent with the provisions of the New York State Internet Security and Privacy Act, the New York State Freedom of Information Law, and the New York State Personal Privacy Protection Law. This policy describes what information is collected and how that information is used. Because this privacy policy only applies to this website, you should examine the privacy policy of any website, including other State agency and authority websites, that you access using this website.
> 
> For the purposes of this policy, “personal information” means any information concerning a natural person, as opposed to a corporate entity, which, because of name, number, symbol, mark, or other identifier, can be used to identify that natural person. The Authorities and ACS only collect personal information about you when you provide that information voluntarily by sending an e-mail or by initiating an online transaction, such as opening an _E-ZPass_ **®** account or viewing and modifying an existing _E-ZPass_ **®** account.
> 
> Information Collected Automatically When You Visit this Website   
>  When you visit this website, the Authorities and ACS automatically collect and store the following information about your visit:
> 
>   * User client hostname. Your hostname or Internet Protocol Address. The Internet Protocol Address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer. 
>   * HTTP header, user agent. The type of browser you are using, its version, and the operating system on which that browser is running. 
>   * HTTP header, referrer. The web page from which you accessed this web page. 
>   * System date. The date and time of your request. 
>   * Full request. Your exact request. 
>   * Status. The status code the server returned to you. 
>   * Content Length. The content length, in bytes, of any document sent to you. 
>   * Method. The request method used. 
>   * Universal Resource Identifier (URI). The location of a resource on the server. 
>   * Query string of the URI. Anything after the question mark in a URI. 
>   * Protocol. The transport protocol and the version used. 
> 
None of the foregoing information is deemed to constitute personal information.
> 
> The Authorities and ACS use the information that is collected automatically to improve this website's content and to help the Authorities and ACS understand how users are interacting with the website. The Authorities and ACS collect this information for statistical analysis, to determine what information is of most and least interest to our users, and to improve the utility of the material available on the website. The information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes and the Authorities and ACS do not sell or otherwise disclose the information collected from this website for commercial marketing purposes.
> 
> Cookies  
>  Cookies are simple text files stored on your web browser to provide a means of distinguishing among users of this website. The use of cookies is a standard practice among Internet websites. To better serve you, the Authorities and ACS may use “session cookies” to enhance or customize your visit to this website. Session cookies can be created automatically on the device you use to access this website. These session cookies do not contain personal information and do not compromise your privacy or security. The Authorities and ACS may use the cookie feature to store a randomly generated identifying tag on the device you use to access this website. A session cookie is erased during operation of your browser or when your browser is closed. 
> 
> At times you may be asked if you would like to personalize this website by allowing the Authorities and ACS to store a “persistent cookie” on your computer’s hard drive. This persistent cookie will allow the website to recognize you when you visit again and tailor the information presented to you based on your needs and interests. The Authorities and ACS use persistent cookies only with your permission.
> 
> The software and hardware you use to access this website allows you to refuse new cookies or delete existing cookies. Refusing or deleting these cookies may limit your ability to take advantage of some features of this website.
> 
> Information Collected When You E-mail this Website or Initiate an Online Transaction   
>  During your visit to this website you may send an email or submit a feedback form to the Authorities and ACS. If so, the Authorities and ACS will collect your e-mail address and the contents of your message. The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video and graphic information formats included in the message. The Authorities and ACS may use your e-mail address and the information included in your message to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve this website, or to forward your message to another State agency or authority for appropriate action. The Authorities and ACS do not collect your e-mail address for commercial purposes and the Authorities and ACS do not sell or otherwise disclose your e-mail address for commercial purposes.
> 
> During your visit to this website you may initiate a transaction such as opening an _E-ZPass_ **®** account or viewing and modifying an existing _E-ZPass_ **®** account. The Authorities and ACS may use the information, including personal information, that you volunteered by initiating the transaction to open, operate and maintain your _E-ZPass_ **®** account, such as periodic notices, correspondence and statements. The Authorities and ACS may disclose such information for those purposes that may be reasonably ascertained from the nature and terms of the transaction in connection with which the information was submitted.
> 
> The Authorities and ACS do not knowingly collect personal information from children or create profiles of children through this website. Users are cautioned, however, that the Authorities and ACS will treat personal information submitted in an e-mail or transaction as though it was submitted by an adult, and such information may, unless exempted from access by federal or State law, be subject to public access. The Authorities and ACS strongly encourage parents and teachers to be involved in children’s Internet activities and to provide guidance whenever children are asked to provide personal information online.
> 
> Information and Choice  
>  As noted above, the Authorities and ACS do not collect any personal information about you during your visit to this website unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending an email, submitting an online form, or initiating an online transaction such as opening an _E-ZPass_ **®** account or viewing and modify an existing _E-ZPass_ **®** account. You may choose not to send the Authorities and ACS an e-mail, submit an online form or initiate an online transaction. While your choice not to participate in these activities may limit your ability to receive specific services or products through this website, it will not prevent you from requesting services or products from the Authorities and ACS by other means and will not normally have an impact on your ability to take advantage of other features of the website, including browsing or downloading publicly available information.
> 
> Disclosure of Information Collected Through This Website   
>  For the New York Authorities, and ACS when acting on behalf of the New York Authorities, the collection of information through this website and the disclosure of that information are subject to the provisions of the New York State Internet Security and Privacy Act. The Authorities and ACS will only collect personal information through this website or disclose personal information collected through this website if the user has consented to the collection or disclosure of such personal information. The user’s participation in an online transaction resulting in the disclosure of personal information to the Authorities and ACS, whether solicited or unsolicited, constitutes consent to the Authorities’ and ACS’ collection and disclosure of the information for the purposes for which the user disclosed the information to the Authorities and ACS, as was reasonably ascertainable from the nature and terms of the transaction.
> 
> However, the Authorities and ACS may collect or disclose personal information without user consent if the collection or disclosure is: (1) necessary to perform the statutory duties of the Authorities, or necessary for the Authorities to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by state or federal statute or regulation; (2) made pursuant to a court order, subpoena or by law; (3) for the purpose of validating the identity of the user; or (4) of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in a form that cannot be used to identify any particular person.
> 
> Further, for the New York Authorities, and ACS when acting on behalf of the New York Authorities, the disclosure of information, including personal information, collected through this website is subject to the provisions of the New York State Freedom of Information Law and the New York State Personal Privacy Protection Law. 
> 
> The Authorities and ACS may disclose personal information to federal or state law enforcement authorities to enforce the Authorities’ and ACS’ rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to the Authorities’ and ACS’ information technology assets or against other inappropriate uses of this website.
> 
> Retention of Information Collected Through this Website  
>  In general, the Authorities’ and ACS’ Internet services logs, comprised of electronic files or automated logs created to monitor access and use of Authority and ACS services provided through this website, will be retained for 30 days and then destroyed. Information, including personal information, that you submit in an e-mail or when you initiate an online transaction such as opening an _E-ZPass_ **®** account or viewing and modifying an existing _E-ZPass_ **®** account, is retained in accordance with the records retention and disposition schedule established for the records of the program unit to which you submitted the information. 
> 
> Access to and Correction of Personal Information Collected Through this Website  
>  Any user may submit a request to the Privacy Compliance Officer of the Authority that maintains the user’s account to determine whether personal information pertaining to that user has been collected through this website. Any such request shall be made in writing to the address below and must be accompanied by reasonable proof of identity of the user. Reasonable proof of identity may include verification of a signature, inclusion of an identifier generally known only to the user, or similar appropriate identification. The address of the Privacy Compliance Officer for each Authority is:
> 
> Privacy Compliance Officer  
>  New York State Thruway Authority  
>  200 Southern Boulevard  
>  Albany, NY 12209
> 
> Privacy Compliance Officer  
>  Metropolitan Transportation Authority   
>  2 Broadway  
>  New York, NY 10004
> 
> Privacy Compliance Officer  
>  Port Authority of New York & New Jersey  
>  1 Madison Avenue  
>  New York, NY 10010
> 
> Privacy Compliance Officer  
>  New York State Bridge Authority  
>  P.O. Box 1010  
>  Highland, NY 12528
> 
> The Privacy Compliance Officer shall, within five (5) business days of the date of the receipt of a proper request: (i) provide access to the personal information; (ii) deny access in writing, explaining the reasons therefore; or (iii) acknowledge the receipt of the request in writing, stating the approximate date when the request will be granted or denied, which date shall not be more than thirty (30) days from the date of the acknowledgment.
> 
> In the event that a New York Authority has collected personal information pertaining to a user through this website and that information is to be provided to the user pursuant to the user’s request, the Privacy Compliance Officer shall inform the user of his or her right to request that the personal information be amended or corrected under the procedures set forth in section 95 of the New York State Public Officers Law.
> 
> Confidentiality and Integrity of Personal Information Collected Through this Website  
>  The Authorities and ACS are strongly committed to protecting personal information collected through this website against unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. Consequently, the Authorities and ACS limit employee access to personal information collected through this website to only those employees who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties. Employees who have access to this information are required to follow appropriate procedures in connection with any disclosure of personal information.
> 
> In addition, the Authorities and ACS have implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of their information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of this website as part of the Authorities’ and ACS’ continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information.
> 
> For website security purposes and to maintain the availability of the website for all users, the Authorities employ software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage this website.
> 
> Disclaimer  
>  The information provided in this privacy policy should not be construed as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof the security of information provided through this website.
> 
> Links  
>  In order to provide users with certain information, the Authorities and ACS may provide links to the websites of local, State, and federal government agencies, and to the websites of other organizations. A link does not constitute an endorsement of the content, viewpoint, accuracy, opinions, policies, products, services, or accessibility of that website. Once you link to another website from this website, including one maintained by the State, you are subject to the terms and conditions of that website, including, but not limited to, its Internet privacy policy.
